SAMUEL OLUWATOBI BABALOLA

10 Greenwood Street, New Britain, CT

(860) 938 1439 | sammytech.net@gmail.com | http://sammytech.me/ | https://github.com/sammytech

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Objective

A self-motivated programmer with 6+ years of programming, who is willing to learn. Seeking to leverage my experience to increase company's productivity. To gain additional experience in software development. To be part of a mission to develop software used by variety of people.

Core Competencies

Programming • Problem Solving • Relational Database • Mobile Development • Android Development iOS development • Software Development • Backend Development

Technical Competencies

<u>Applications</u>: Android Studio • XCode • Eclipse • IntelliJ • Microsoft Office • phpMyAdmin • Git

<u>Languages</u>: Java • Swift • Python • PHP • C • C++ • MIPS • HTML • CSS • MySQL • Node.js

Javascript • React-Native • Angular

Platforms: OSX • Windows • Linux • AWS

Professional Experience

Evolution Radio, Indianapolis, IN

06/2015 – 06/2016

(Software Developer Freelancer)

- Designed and created the application for both Android and iOS platforms.
- Reduced cost of developing the mobile application by recommending the usage of a MBaaS (Mobile Backend as a Service) platform Backendless.
- Created a web application to manage push notification in the mobile application.
- Communicated frequently with the client on the progress of the application.
- Successfully submitted mobile application to the apple and play store.
- Recommended technical solutions that helped the company determine the user interface of their website.

Vuse LLC, Rochester, NY

11/2014- 04/2016

(Software Developer)

Univent

04/2015 – 04/2016

A mobile application which gave students at college campuses the ability to be aware of events around them.

- Created the Android version of the mobile application
- Managed a team of 4 developers
- Created the RESTful API used by all the application
- Created a web scrapper to get information from specific websites
- Successfully submitted mobile application to the play store
- Delivered a weekly/bi-weekly update on the progress of the application.
- Designed and implemented the database

Vlipd

11/2014 - 03/2015

A mobile application which allowed users to record, share and collaborate with other users.

- Presented mobile application at Imagine RIT
- Developed the application for iOS
- Accelerated development by using a MBaaS (Mobile Backend as a Service) platform Parse.

Projects

Trafex 03/2017 - Present

A mobile application which allows students on a college campus to buy, sell, and exchange books among each other

- Using Parse Server (open source API server written in Node.js)
- Currently developing for android devices
- Using MongoDB

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Graduating in December 2017, The College at Brockport, SUNY; Brockport, NY

Relevant Courses

Object Oriented Software Development

Created a library system, which allows a worker to add, and modify books', workers', and students' information. This system was built using Java and MySQL

Associate of Science, Computer Science

Graduated in May 2016, Monroe Community College; Rochester, NY

Relevant Courses

Programming Embedded Micro-controller in C and Assembly

Developed a motorized robot using a DragonBoard Micro-controller.

Concepts of Parallel and Distributed Systems

Developed a server-client desktop application in Java. This application allowed users to play a two player dice game over a network. The application pairs users up whenever there is another available player.